Eric Frey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- 337-849-3523

- ericlfrey.com



- ericlfrey@gmail.com



- github.com/ericlfrey



in - linkedin.com/in/ericlfrey

OVERVIEW

I specialize in creating applications with React, Next.js, JavaScript, Python, and Django. My experience extends to AWS, Electron, Firebase, Tailwind, and Bootstrap. I am highly motivated to develop innovative and userfriendly web applications, and I am committed to continuous learning and growth in the field.

SKILLS

 React Python AWS

C#

Next JS

Django

SQL

.NET

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | June 2023 - Present

- Experience in developing and maintaining user-centric software applications.
- Contributed to various projects, including a digital archive, a company website, and a SaaS Electron app in a Scrum environment.
- Led the development of an artist's digital archive, optimizing media management with Cloudinary.
- Played a pivotal role in company website development, enhancing the user interface and integrating the Atlassian API for improved content engagement.
- Contributed to SaaS Electron app development and continuously learned about emerging technologies.
- Earned the AWS Cloud Quest: Cloud Practitioner badge, showcasing expertise in cloud computing.

Nashville Software School | September 2022 - Present

Junior Instructor

- Instruction of software development, collaborating with senior instructors.
- Fostered a dynamic and engaging learning environment.
- · Contributed to curriculum enhancements and virtual classroom management.

Software Developer Apprentice

- · Daily hands-on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects
- Created single page applications in JavaScript, as well as in the React and Next.is frameworks
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking
- Source code/version control with Git/GitHub
- Solution Design: white-boarding and wireframes
- Leveraged Django for creating and editing server-generated web applications
- Created RESTful APIs with Django REST framework
- Retrieved and stored database information with SQLite
- Practiced testing with Python's unit test framework

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

840 Inspections | January 2020 - May 2023

Home Inspection company that also provides radon testing, thermal imaging, and environmental testing.

TN Licensed Home Inspector

- Assisted in growing the company to be a multi-inspector firm.
- Increased the company's revenue by 50% by expanding our customer base and developing new marketing strategies.
- Developed and maintained relationships with real estate agents and their clients.
- Managed other inspectors in the field and provided them with training and support.
- Responsible for continuous research on related topics and systems, and staying up-to-date on industry trends to ensure that the company is using the latest and most effective technologies and practices.

Professional Musician | September 2003 - January 2020

- Tour manager with experience in advance work and road management.
- Grammy-nominated multi-instrumentalist and producer with over 50 recording credits, including HBO and film placements.
- Experience co-founding a music festival and booking/managing a stage.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School 2022 - 2023 Full Stack Web Development **University of Alabama at Birmingham** 1999 - 2003 Music Technology

PROJECTS

The Soap Dish Live Site Demo GitHub

The Soap Dish is a full stack app built with a React/NextJS front end, and Python/Django back end that allows soap-makers to create, share, and save favorite soap recipes. TSD uses Bootstrap for both desktop and mobile responsive design.

Get Shit Done Live Site Demo GitHub

Get Shit Done is a full-stack project planning application that helps users stay organized and manage multiple projects simultaneously. It allows users to create, read, update, and delete projects, tasks, and materials. The app is built with React Hooks, Next.js Routes, Django, Google Firebase for Auth, and Bootstrap to provide a clean and user-friendly experience.

HireFrame Live Site GitHub

HireFrame is a job search tracking application that helps users stay organized and manage their job prospects more efficiently. It allows users to create a customizable kanban-style board to track the status of their job applications, filter and sort opportunities, and set due dates for follow-up tasks. Built with React Hooks, Next.js Routes, Google Firebase, and Bootstrap, HireFrame offers a user-friendly and streamlined experience to help users land their dream job.